A Guide to the Wayne Hill Stereoview Collection, 1871-1909
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Wayne Hill Stereoview Collection, 1871-1909
Fairfax County Public Library
2015.166
0.6 linear feet
The Wayne Hill Stereoview Collection consists of 71 stereoviews depicting scenes throughout Virginia including Fairfax County. The collection spans the years 1871-1909, although many are undated and some depict images from the Civil War era. Wayne Hill, a local photographer, collected and owned these stereoviews.
Hill, Wayne
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Collection donated December 31, 2015 by Wayne Hill.
Historical and Biographical Information
Wayne Hill, a local photographer, collected stereoviews over a period of years. Born in Washington D.C., Hill attended Dartmouth College and graduated in 1966 with a B.A. in Environmental Psychology. After working with noted photographic artist Ansel Adams in California, Hill started his own company in Virginia called The HILL Art Group. For fifty years, Hill’s company has focused on photographing American National Parks and other scenic locations around the globe. In addition to his many artistic accomplishments and awards, Hill is the former President and CEO of Leadership Fairfax, Inc. and a former Board Member of the Fairfax County Chamber of Commerce and Greater Reston Chamber of Commerce.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
Index Terms
Arlington National Cemetery; Fairfax County, Virginia; Mount Vernon (Estate); Virginia - Photographic Images
Container List
- The Marshall House Alexandria, Va Publisher: Taylor & Huntington, Undated; WAYNE-001
- Arlington National Cemetery [2 copies] Arlington, Va Publisher: Bell & Bro, Undated; WAYNE-002
- Distant Washington from the Heights of Arlington National Cemetery, Va. Arlington, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-003
- General Lee's Old Homestead, Arlington Va Arlington, Va Publisher: J.T. Jarvis Publisher, Underwood & Underwood, Undated; WAYNE-004
- General Robert E Lee's Old Home Arlington, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-005
- General Robert E Lee's Old Home (N.W.) at Arlington VA Arlington, Va Publisher: Underwood & Underwood, Undated; WAYNE-006
- General Robert E. Lee's Old Home, Arlington, VA Arlington, Va Publisher: Underwood & Underwood, 1903; WAYNE-007
- National Cemetery, Arlington, Va. [graves] Arlington, Va Publisher: Bell & Bro, 1871; WAYNE-008
- National Cemetery, Arlington, Va. [Unknown Civil War soldiers monument] (Inscription: "Bought at Arlington May 21, 1872") Arlington, Va Publisher: Bell & Bro, 1871; WAYNE-009
- Soldiers' Graves, Arlington, Va. Arlington, Va Publisher: J.T. Jarvis Publisher, Underwood & Underwood, Undated; WAYNE-010
- Soldiers' Graves, Arlington, Va. [children pictured] Arlington, Va Publisher: J.T. Jarvis Publisher, Underwood & Underwood, Undated; WAYNE-011
- The Arlington House Arlington, Va Publisher: Bell & Bro, Undated; WAYNE-012
- A Pontoon Boat On Wheels Boat Publisher: Taylor & Huntington, Undated; WAYNE-013
- Call again Girls Camp Alger, Va Publisher: Griffith & Griffith, 1898; WAYNE-014
- Prof. Lowe observing the Battle of Fair Oaks, Va from his balloon. Fair Oaks, Va Publisher: E & H. T. Anthony & Co., Undated; WAYNE-015
- Fairfax Court House and its surruondings, taken just after the Grand Army passed to fight the battle of Bull Run, 1861 Fairfax, Va Publisher: E. Anthony, Undated; WAYNE-016
- A mountain of oyster shells used as "bedding" for young oysters, Hampton, Va. Hampton, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, 1909; WAYNE-017
- A mountain of oysters Ready for Planting - Oyster Culture Hampton, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, 1909; WAYNE-018
- Fortress Monroe, Old Point Comfort, Va. Hampton, Va Publisher: H.C. White Company, 1901; WAYNE-019
- U.S. Battleships (Connecticut in lead) steaming out to sea Hampton Roads, Va Publisher: Underwood & Underwood, Undated; WAYNE-020
- Ruins of the Old Church Jamestown, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-021
- The Old Colonial Chruch, Restored Jamestown, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-022
- General Robert E. Lee Lee, Robert E. Publisher: Taylor & Huntington, Undated; WAYNE-023
- General View of Camp 2, Army Maneuvers Manassas, Va Publisher: H.C. White Company, 1905; WAYNE-024
- Home of Thomas Jefferson [2 copies] Monticello, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-025
- A Nation's Shrine - Home of Washington, Founder of the Republic, Mount Vernon, Va. Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-026
- A Nation's Shrine - Home of Washington, Founder of the Republic, Mount Vernon, Va. [4 copies] Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-027
- A Nation's shrine from the Air - Home of Washington, Founder of the Republic [3 copies] Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-028
- Home of Washington - Mt. Vernon Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: J.T. Jarvis Publisher, Undated; WAYNE-029
- Home of Washington, preserved in memory of the Republic's founder, Mount Vernon, Virginia. Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: Underwood & Underwood, 1908; WAYNE-030
- Mount Vernon, The Residence of George Washington Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: E. & H. T. Anthony & Company, Undated; WAYNE-031
- Mt. Vernon, the Home of Washington Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-032
- State Dining Room, Wahington's Old Home, Mt. Vernon Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, 1898; WAYNE-033
- Washington's bed and room where he died, December 14, 1799, Mount Vernon Mansion Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: Mount Vernon Ladies' Union Association, Undated; WAYNE-034
- Washington's Home, Mt. Vernon Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: Underwood & Underwood, 1896; WAYNE-035
- Washington's Old Home, Mt. Vernon Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, 1898; WAYNE-036
- Washington's Room, Mt. Vernon, Va Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-037
- West View of Mt. Vernon Mansion Mount Vernon, Va Publisher: Mount Vernon Ladies' Union Association, Undated; WAYNE-038
- Baptizing in Cedar Creek under the Great Natural Bridge, Va Natural Bridge, VA Publisher: Keystone View Company, 1898; WAYNE-039
- One of Nature's Curiosities, The Natural Bridge in Virginia Natural Bridge, VA Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-040
- One of Nature's Curiosities, The Natural Bridge in Virginia Natural Bridge, VA Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-041
- Military Parade in Front of the Auditroum Building - Opening Day at the Jamestown Exposition, April 26, 1907 Norfolk, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, WAYNE-042
- Panorama of the Lee Parade Ground Which Covers 30 Acres Norfolk, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, 1907; WAYNE-043
- Spraying with Arsenate of Lead, Truck Gardens Norfolk, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-044
- General View of Norfolk Navy yard Portsmouth, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-045
- Canal Basin Richmond, Va Publisher: Anderson's StereoScopic Views, Undated; WAYNE-046
- Capitol of the Old Dominion, Once Capitol of the Confederate States [3 copies] Richmond, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-047
- Castle Thunder, (Confederate Prison) Richmond, Va Publisher: Virginia Centennial Views, Undated; WAYNE-048
- Exchange and Ballard Hotels Richmond, Va Publisher: E. S. Lumpkin & CO, Undated; WAYNE-049
- General Lee's Residence Richmond, Va Publisher: Anderson Gallery, Undated; WAYNE-050
- James River Pontoon Bridge, opened for the passage of Steamers Richmond, Va Publisher: E & H.T. Anthony and CO, Undated; WAYNE-051
- View of Main Street Richmond, Va Publisher: Cook. Anderson Gallery, Undated; WAYNE-052
- Washington Monument Richmond, Va Publisher: Selden & Co., Undated; WAYNE-053
- Washington's Old Headquarters, The Oldest Building in Richmond, Va Richmond, Va Publisher: Berry, Kelly & Chadwich, 1907; WAYNE-054
- Mountain Valley from the Skyline Drive, Shenandoah National Park, Va Shenandoah National Park, Va Publisher: Keystone View Company, Undated; WAYNE-055
- The New U.S. Battleship "Maine" USS Maine Publisher: Unknown, Undated; WAYNE-056
- Pennsylvania Ave., Inauguration Day B. Washington D.C. Publisher: Selected Series, American Cities, Undated; WAYNE-057